Melanie MacDonald

melmacd94@gmail.com | 240-678-4367

https://github.com/mmacdonald1 https://linkedin.com/in/melanie-macdonald1 http://www.melmacd.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Knowledgeable Software Developer with 4 years of experience in coding and leading development teams. Motivated self starter who can execute tasks with minimal supervision. Seeking ground breaking companies where I can dive deeper into and expand upon my product development and engineering skill sets with a team.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript (Expert), Ruby (Advanced), Java (Intermediate), Python (Intermediate)

Frontend Frameworks: React (Expert), Angular (Expert), Preact (Expert), Ruby on Rails (Advanced)

Libraries: Redux (Expert), Mobx-State-Tree (Expert), D3.js (Advanced), Chart.js (Expert)

Backend Technologies: Node (Expert), Express (Advanced), Nest.js (Advanced), Spring (Intermediate), Ruby

on Rails (Advanced)

Databases: PostgreSQL (Advanced), MySQL (Advanced), MongoDB (Advanced), Oracle (Intermediate)

EXPERIENCE

Terrayn Dispensary Marketing

August 2020 - Present

Founding Software Engineer

- Collaborating with founders to bring ideas into reality, from conducting market research to writing a business plan, designing application architecture, and managing a development team
- Continuing ownership by defining product and engineering roadmaps, networking and interviewing clients for beta, and teaching designers, engineers, and contacts full-stack development skills
- Leading frontend development and contributing to backend development of an application with a React, Mobx, Nest.js, Postgres, and Flask stack

Consequa Technology

September 2019 - August 2020

Software Engineer

- Completing development of 3 applications by upgrading the framework, adding OIDC role-based authentication, creating custom D3.js graphics, designing WebSocket infrastructure, and modifying existing libraries to add desired features
- Contributing to the development and maintenance of a financial application, including creating two specialized document search modules and a major refactor of the contract tracking module
- Leading and mentoring development team in reaching higher code quality, developing documentation, and increasing subject knowledge which accelerated our teams' ability to meet client expectations

Synergy Software Design

April 2019 - September 2019

Web Application Developer

- Acting as the subject matter expert for React, Redux, and JavaScript architecture practices to create reusable and sustainable code
- Developing interfaces for the Navy to upload, analyze, and view large scale data to make more informed financial decisions
- Optimizing 3d interfaces, presentation features, and advanced calendar integrations for input in future projects on legacy computer systems

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Program Bachelor of Arts in Biology, Minor Studio Art

January 2018

May 2016

St. Mary's College of Maryland, St. Mary's City, MD